<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Getting started with Decision Support">
   <intro
         href="/net.bioclipse.ds/html/maintopic.html">
      <description>
         <b>Decision Support</b>
This tutorial describes the basic steps for using the Decision Support feature of Bioclipse. For this tutorial it is good, but not necessary, to have Sample Data installed. 
      </description>
   </intro>

   <item
         title="Step 1: Open the Decision Support Perspective">
      <description>
         The <b>Decision Support Perspective</b> is a setup of the workbench which is suitable for the Decision Support feature.
<br/><br/>
In the top menu, select option <b>Window &gt; Open Perspective &gt; Other...</b> and in the dialog select the <b>Decision Support option</b>.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=net.bioclipse.ds.ui.perspective)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Step 2: Open a chemical structure">
      <description>
         In the Bioclipse Navigator, double-click a chemical structure to open it in the chemical editor. It is also possible to edit molecules.
      </description>
    <action
			pluginId="net.bioclipse.scripting.ui"
			class="net.bioclipse.scripting.ui.actions.ScriptAction"
	        required="false"
			param1="mol=cdk.fromSMILES(&quot;CCCCON=O&quot;)"
			param2="mol=cdk.generate2dCoordinates(mol)"
			param3="ui.open(mol)"
			/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Step 3: Run the Tests">
      <description>
         The Tests can be run by right clicking in the Decision Support tab or by clicking the "Run all tests" button (with a 'play' icon) in the Decision Support View. 
      </description>
    <action
			pluginId="net.bioclipse.ds"
			class="net.bioclipse.ds.actions.CheatRunAction"
	        required="false"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Step 4: Examine the Test results.">
      <description>
         Each individual test can be examined by expanding it and selecting the results. If the test displays substructures, as for the Signature Significance, then the atoms that belongs to the substructure will be displayed in the chemical editor. Entire molecules will be displayed in the 2D viewer. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Step 5: Generate a report">
      <description>
         By right clicking in the Decision Support tab it is possible to generate a Report. Note that it takes over 20 seconds to open the first report, while after this generating reports is much faster.
      </description>
    <action
			pluginId="net.bioclipse.ds"
			class="net.bioclipse.ds.actions.CheatReportAction"
	        required="false"/>
   </item>
   
      <item
         title="Step 6: Open an SDFile">
      <description>
         In the Bioclipse Navigator, double-click an SDFile to open it in the MoleculesTable.
      </description>
    <!--action
			pluginId="net.bioclipse.scripting.ui"
			class="net.bioclipse.scripting.ui.actions.ScriptAction"
	        required="false"
			param1="lst=cdk.createMoleculeList()"
			param2="lst.add(cdk.fromSMILES(&quot;CCCCON=O&quot;)"
			param3="lst.add(cdk.fromSMILES(&quot;S3CC4C1NC1C2CSC(C)C2C4(C3)&quot;)"
			param4="ui.open(lst)"
			/-->
   </item>
      <item 
         title="Step 7: Calculate all tests and consensus">
      <description>
         Right-click in the MoleculesTable and select Decision Support > Consensus Classification
      </description>
   </item>
      <item 
         title="Step 8: Switch between tabs in the Molecules Table">
      <description>
         Select one of the structures in the MoleculesTable and then click the tab <b>Single molecule</b> at the bottom of the editor. Here you can run individual tests, make changes to the molecule, and when you switch back to the tab <b>Molecules</b> the updated values are calculated in the background and the visualization is updated (just wait a few seconds for it to complete).
      </description>
   </item>
      <item 
         title="More information">
      <description>
         This step concludes this tutorial. For more information, please refer to the Bioclipse Help system available from the top menu <b>Help > Help Contents</b>.
      </description>
          <command
          required="false"
          serialization="org.eclipse.ui.help.displayHelp(href=/net.bioclipse.ds/html/maintopic.html)"/>
      
   </item>
   
</cheatsheet>
